Bruno .
Let 's go .
" I love you , Margherita , passionately , desperately ... "
" I 'm not interested in who you really are . "
- Listen to her . - They probably planned it .
They 're coming ! They 're coming !
Give me a cigarette .
- They 're strong , what are they ? - Gauloise .
- Isn 't Tonino coming ? - He 's taking the day off .
Michele . Bruno .
They 're coming . I saw them , they 're coming .
- They 're coming , I saw their car . - What do they look like ?
They 're really fat , with tits like melons , and an ass like this !
Then let 's go .
- Let me have a drag . - It 's a Gauloise .
- It 's strong . - Come on .
- Let go , it 's mine . - Did you bring the money ?
- Yes , I 've got it . - Hurry up .
Come on .
" We 'll be at the castle soon , and you 'll meet my mother . "
- Maria , he invited her to the castle . - Just imagine the mother now ...
She was already upset in the last episode .
- Good morning , ladies . - She 's trying to listen .
- Okay , let 's go , guys . - Wasn 't he the prince in the other story ?
- He committed suicide . - I can 't hear it .
The other story was better .
We want to make love , we 're not interested in the radio .
- We 've been waiting all morning . - How can I forget ?
It was such a moving story .
I like these stories because they make me cry .
- Who 's he ? - No , let him watch , he 's crazy .
- Let 's make this quick . - We have to be quick as well .
- Get a move on . - At least turn off this radio .
No . Hold on .
Wait a minute .
If you don 't pay , you can 't watch .
Barra .
Come in and enjoy the show .
Barra 's a peeping tom .
If I catch you I 'll kill you .
I 'll kill you .
- Hi , mum . - Pick up your jacket .
Someone finally makes an appearance in this house .
Wash your hands .
You have to take this orangeade to the lady of the house .
She 's resting .
She must be tired , poor thing .
Your father 's been playing cards all day , and who knows where you 've been ?
- But it 's Sunday tomorrow . - Right ...
I 'm the only who never gets a day off . Everyone gets a day off ...
But not me !
I 'm never tired , I 'm everyone 's servant .
I wash , iron , cook , I clean the house ...
And what do the others do ?
- Where are you going ? - I put your orangeade here .
Well pour some out , and bring it here .
- Hurry up , I 'm thirsty . - Yes , yes , I 'm coming !
Go on , look at me .
Had a good look ?
Is it the first time you 've seen a woman naked ?
No .
Tell me ...
How many girls have you slept with ?
- A lot ! - No , you 're a liar .
If you said one or two I 'd have believed you ...
But if you say a lot then it 's not true .
You 're a real chatterbox .
Would you like to do it with me ?
Come on , answer me .
Yes .
I 'm sure you would .
Michele .
Yes , mum .
I 'm coming .
Go on , run to mummy .
What 's wrong with you tonight ? Shut up .
You never let me sleep .
" The search for little Bruno Locascio ... "
" Continued all day yesterday . "
" Comma ... "
" The fourth day since his disappearance . "
If they kept their kids at home .
And who gets thrown in the middle ? Us , these poor dogs ...
" The search is covering a wide area ... "
" Comma ... "
" With a task force of around a hundred police officers ... "
" And with help from the dog unit . "
The latest revelation came a short while ago ...
It would appear that the boy 's father ...
Received an anonymous phone call ...
With a request for a large sum , as ransom .
Yes .
The investigating officers aren 't saying very much .
Yes . That 's everything .
Stop .
I 'm sorry , the deputy public prosecutor is here , you can 't go in .
I understand , thanks . Relax .
I 'll show them what Martelli is capable of .
But we don 't have that kind of money .
Everyone knows . We 're poor folk .
All we have is this piece of land that isn 't worth anything ...
And two pieces of bread .
- Are you sure you don 't have any enemies ? - Enemies ? Us ?
We get on with everyone .
He only wants money . Only money !
Six thousand in cash , he said .
Where does he want it ?
I must bring it to the abandoned factory , half an hour before sunset .
He wants me to hide it inside the third boiler .
- Who 's going to give us six thousand ? - in cash ?
Right ...
Of course it has to be in cash .
Did you add that , or did he tell you on the phone ?
No , no ... On the phone .
That 's what he said . All of it , in cash .
- All of it in cash . - Yes .
I 'm sorry , prosecutor , but bear with me ...
Think about it for a moment , if you ask me ...
This blackmailer must be a little crazy don 't you think ?
Yes . Yes , it 's true .
To stipulate something so obvious .
- Sorry , who are you ? - Andrea Martelli , the Milan Standard .
How did you get in ? Who let you through ?
Nobody . The window was open ...
Listen , you 've pointed out something interesting ...
- But I 'd like you to leave now . - Yes , sure , as you wish . Morning .
No ! Not this way ...
- Please , the other door . - Okay , I get it .
- Morning . - Good morning .
- Well , Locascio ? - He said ...
That I must go there alone .
And if I tried anything , he said ...
- He said he 'd kill him ! - He 'll kill him !
He 'll kill him if you don 't bring the money .
- My God ! - Don 't cry .
- Help us ! - We 'll find a solution .
- Stop ! - Stop .
You can 't get away .
Stop !
I put my hand inside , like that , Marshal .
By chance ?
I always hide something in that boiler , Marshal ...
My things .
Listen , who the hell do you think you are , Barra ?
I 'm telling you the truth . I don 't know anything .
I didn 't even know who this Bruno Locascio was .
What do you mean ' was ' ?
Why don 't you say ' is ' ?
Because you know he 's dead .
It 's true .
You killed him , Barra .
- Confess . - I don 't know anything .
That kid was only twelve years old , and you killed him ...
Confess ! You killed him !
I didn 't kill him . I swear .
I had nothing to do with it . I didn 't kill him , officer .
Yes ?
It 's me .
You just have to check something ...
Listen to this voice .
- Say something . - What ?
Whatever you like . You know how to count ... Count .
One , two , three ...
Go on !
One , two ...
I haven 't done anything !
What do you think ?
Are you certain ?
Yes , of course . I 'll keep you informed .
- Well ? - Locascio ...
He recognised his voice .
Murderer .
We 'd better get him away from here ...
- Have him transferred to the city . - Yes , sir .
Modesti .
- Take him away . - You can 't arrest me .
- I 'm Martelli , from the Standard . - Yes , I remember you ...
But I can 't talk to you , sorry .
Did you hear that ? He says the kid was already dead .
Don 't listen to him , he 's crazy . You said so yourself .
The people want a culprit .
And we have to find one , before they do .
Then you 're not ruling out that Barra might be telling the truth ?
You know he contradicted himself a number of times ...
- It 's all here , in his statement . - Yes ...
But those contradictions are so absurd , they confirm he has a low IQ .
- You 've known him for many years . - Yes , I already told you ...
- He has never hurt anyone . - He finds the boy in the forest , dead ...
Then he hides the body , to extort money from the boy 's father .
A flash of genius , from a lunatic .
Right , also the modest amount he asked for , just 6000 ...
Seems to confirm your hypothesis .
- This one hadn 't been molested , either . - Inform the press ...
So we can put a stop to the rumours that the crimes were sexual .
The only variation between the two crimes
is a contusion on the neck of the first victim .
Yes , the killer stunned him , before killing him .
He could 've beaten him to death , but he didn 't ...
He strangled him , like the second one .
In my opinion this indicates a definite choice ...
The kind of manic repetition we find in schizophrenics .
Well , someone who kills two young boys must have something wrong with him .
- Excuse me , Lieutenant . - We all agree ...
The killer is a lunatic .
But even a lunatic , in his mad logic ...
Must have had a reason .
Were the victims unrelated ...
Or do we have to start looking at them to find a motive ?
Yes , I probably knew them better than anyone .
On your head , Nicola !
That 's what I thought ...
When a priest is close to the kids , even his age .
Yes , sure . That helps a lot .
They 're better off here , than on the streets .
Pass the ball .
They must be good kids , after all , if they prefer God 's house to the streets .
Let 's say the football pitch .
They 're quite devoted to God , but very devoted to Football ...
Very .
They really like you , everyone in the village says so .
Yes , I know . But do you know what my secret is ?
- I 'm listening . - I also play football .
And I 'm a good centre-forward .
These are sad times , people watch television ...
They go to the cinema , that 's how it is .
They read newspapers with those scandalous photos .
You 're a journalist . You know .
Yes , but I work for a daily .
Then something bad happens , and everyone wonders why !
No , there 's no water . They turn it off at five o 'clock .
- This as well . - So they look for a culprit ...
And nobody understands that it 's our tolerance that 's to blame .
What can a poor priest do ?
I 'm friends with the news vendor , and he won 't sell certain magazines ...
They don 't even arrive here .
Go on , take it .
It 's a kind of censorship .
- Why ? Is it wrong ? - No ...
- But how do you deal with her ? - Hurry up .
You don 't need a news vendor with her around .
Right .
Don . Alberto , what have they decided in Rome ? Can you marry ?
The male population is on the rise again in the village .
Well , keep me informed , this topic really interests me .
- How much ? - 5000 .
She doesn 't look like one of the devoted faithful .
Who knows ?
A lot of strange things have happened since she arrived .
- What do you mean ? - Nothing ...
In certain cases one can think ill of anybody .
And who 's she ?
Her father is from here , he made his fortune in Milan .
You know that strange , modern , villa you see as you come into the village ?
That 's his ?
He had it built just to annoy the locals , no other reason .
- He never comes here . - Then why is she here ?
A woman like that , in a village like this ?
Seems she was involved with a group of drug addicts .
I don 't know what happened ...
But her father thought a change of scenery would do her good .
Hello ?
It 's you .
What ?
No , I 'm alone . They 're next door .
At this hour ?
Of course I 'll come . I 'll make sure they don 't see me ...
I 'll climb over the wall .
Your keys , lady .
Michele would like this .
Leave him be . He 's studying , for once .
He ate with us at the villa .
Look at this . It was on the boy 's desk .
Why did you return to the annexe so late ?
We had to wait for the lady of the house .
She always asks us to wait until she returns ...
She 's frightened of finding someone in the house ...
I don 't know , some thief .
Find my Michele . I 'm begging you !
Does the lady of the house often go out alone at night ?
No ...
She 's only done it a few times .
It 's pointless , the dogs won 't pick up a scent in this rain .
I 'm soaking wet , I 'm going back to the village ...
- Are you coming with me ? - No , I 'll stay here .
I 'm scared of thieves .
I know it 's foolish , but it 's stronger than me .
But you weren 't scared to go out alone the other night ...
Between nine and midnight , if I 'm not mistaken ?
No . You 're not mistaken .
Of all the things people have told you , at least this is correct .
Do you want to know what I did during those three hours ?
Nothing .
I just drove up and down the motorway like a maniac .
- For three hours ? - Yes .
It 's a great way to let off some steam .
- You must have been very nervous . - I wasn 't nervous , I was ...
What 's the point ?
It 's no use being so mysterious .
With all the gossips in the village I 'm surprised they haven 't told you already .
In the past ...
I did some things I regret . And now I 've stopped ...
- Sometimes I get the urge , and ... - And nobody saw you ?
No , nobody .
Didn 't you stop to fill up ?
To get a coffee ?
I don 't remember .
What do you mean you don 't remember ? We 're talking about last night .
No , I didn 't stop .
- Which one ? - The one with a child in her arms .
The blonde girl .
Is that her daughter ?
Yes , her name 's Malvina . It 's a pity she 's like that ...
Just think , her brother 's very intelligent .
He 's here .
He 's here . He 's here .
I can feel it .
He 's here .
The murderer is here .
He 's here . The murderer is here .
END OF PART ONE
PART TWO
Look , Inspector ...
She went in to the church when everyone else was already inside .
- Well ? - It 's like she didn 't want to be noticed .
- And then ? - She runs away a few minutes later .
- Because that 's a woman running away . - Right .
But this behaviour , this flight from the church ...
Couldn 't it be explained by the fact that she practices black magic ?
No ...
Because , first of all , she doesn 't practice a damned thing ...
They only call her the witch because she 's uncle Francesco 's woman ...
But she isn 't a witch .
Besides , around here , witches , those kind of people ...
- They 're all hand in glove with religion . - Yes , I understand .
And this uncle Francesco , is he some kind of magician ?
Yes , your honour , and he 's quite renowned ...
Just think , people come all the way from Sicily to see him ...
And all around Italy .
- I thought magicians earned more . - They earn !
Uncle Francesco has a bank account just like the rest of us ...
He 's here because he likes it .
He 's spent his whole life in these mountains .
I don 't understand these people .
- Greetings , uncle Francesco . - Long live Italy , son .
Isn 't the witch here ?
If you can 't see her , son , then it means she 's not here .
When will she be back ?
Saint Giuliano knows .
I haven 't seen the witch for two weeks .
And why is that ?
- Who 's he ? - He 's an officer of the law .
If you 're looking for the witch you 're wasting your time ...
She doesn 't do anything bad , and doesn 't know anything bad .
Remember what uncle Francesco 's says .
You haven 't seen her for a while ...
But you 're not worried .
You 're not looking for her .
I looked for her , but she didn 't want to be found .
The last time , I think it was Friday ...
Saint Rocco came to me in a dream and he told me she was in the oak forest .
- And ? - And then ...
I went to have a look .
It rained , the sun went down , and it was night .
- Did you see anyone in the oak forest ? - I saw the night ...
And nothing else .
Saint Rocco is a liar .
You can only trust Saint Biaggio .
He never lies to you .
- Uncle Francesco . - Yes .
You do know a crime was committed in that very place on Friday night ?
I know .
Listen ...
If Saint Biaggio tells me who did it ...
I 'll tell you straight away .
If he 's messing with us I 'll lock him up !
Right , that way we 'll start a revolution in Centura .
Listen , uncle Francesco ...
We just want to ask you a few questions about the witch .
It 's been two weeks since she disappeared .
When is she coming back ?
Only Saint Biaggio and Saint Sebastian know that .
Long live Italy .
If he was telling the truth ...
Only Saint Rocco , Saint Biaggio , and the Holy Father know for sure .
Perhaps he really doesn 't know where she is ...
But one thing is certain , that woman must have a reason to hide .
- Strange pairing , Inspector . - Yes , very strange .
" Take this down ... "
" In latest developments , a contingent of state police has arrived here ... "
" Comma ... "
" From the regional capital . Full stop . "
" Evidently , these men will be used in a search ... "
" Comma ... "
" Which , at this moment , seems pointless ... "
" Given that , thank God , no more children have gone missing . "
You asked me about Don Aurelia Vallone ...
She 's over there , with the girl in her arms .
That 's her ? I saw her in church earlier .
What is she like ?
We only respect her because she 's the priest 's mother .
Hello , Inspector . I know where the witch is hiding .
Yes .
Sure , I know the place .
- Who is this ? - A friend of justice .
We should 've known ...
She saw us coming and she ran off .
- She can 't have gone far . - Tell the helicopter we 're continuing .
- Come on , guys , we 're heading back . - Okay , I 'll tell the others .
The dog has picked up a scent .
- The witch 's son , you say ? - Yes .
... and uncle Francesco .
I 'm talking about fifteen years ago .
She was just a girl when they took her away because she was possessed .
There was a rumour going around at the time ...
That she became pregnant as a result of her chasing away the evil spirits .
But I repeat , it 's just a rumour ...
Because nobody ever saw this boy .
Some said he was still-born , others said he only lived for a few months ...
And that they always kept him hidden , because he was the Devil 's son .
- And who established this paternity ? - Ignorance , Inspector ...
That 's what they say when a baby is born deformed .
But , at the time , Marshal , didn 't you try to find out , to investigate ?
If we listened to everything they say . Besides , I didn 't see anything wrong ...
After all , it was a family accident .
And these three things here , I assume you know what they are .
I don 't know , I 'm not a witch , lieutenant .
Let go of me . Let go of me , you bastards .
It was me .
I gave them death .
Yes , me , to all three of them .
Many times , I had seen Michele playing near my son 's grave .
I watched over it .
- The witch puts these flowers here . - How do you know ?
I saw her .
Bastards . Go away .
- It 's not your land . - You mustn 't come here ever again .
I 'll destroy you .
They had been warned .
But instead ...
They came back the next day , they 'd been digging ...
I 'm sure of it , the ground had been disturbed .
Why didn 't you bury your boy on holy ground ?
I couldn 't .
I couldn 't , he was the Devil 's child .
I told you .
Right .
To conclude ...
You killed all three of them , to punish them , right ?
Yes , sir .
And you didn 't tell anyone , not even uncle Francesco ?
Uncle Francesco is innocent , I swear on Jesus Christ .
I asked him how to ...
But I didn 't tell him why I wanted to know .
And what did you ask uncle Francesco ?
- How to do it . - How to do what ? Strangle them ?
But I didn 't strangle them .
What ?
What are you saying ?
I gave them death , but in a different way .
In what way ?
- I can 't say . - No , you 're going to tell us .
Why does it matter ? I told you I did it .
Put me in jail , it 's finished now .
No , it 's not finished at all .
I brought death to them , just like I warned them .
Sure ...
I warned them .
I 'll destroy you . I 'll destroy you , I told them !
They shouldn 't have done it . But they did .
They did .
They called destiny .
I gave it to them , that 's true , but they wanted it .
I warned them , they shouldn 't have ...
I 'll destroy you , I told them .
They didn 't listen , and I ...
And I ... I made the sign of destiny for them ...
Of death .
Death . Death .
You two , come here .
I made three wax figures ...
Then I painted them black ...
Because that 's the death spell .
I took them ...
And I put pins through them .
You have to do it thirteen times , while you say the words out loud ...
That you need to say it to control the demons .
Thirteen demons .
They start off like that , inside one person 's body ...
From the mouth , and then he does everything .
Who does ?
It can be anyone ...
Man or woman .
Imbalomini , are you sure you 're not confusing it with another night ?
No , Marshal , it was Friday .
You can check the service records .
The night little Michele Spriano was killed ...
I found the witch near the old fort .
- How far is it from the oak forest ? - It 's quite a distance ...
- It 's more than three hours on foot . - Are you sure it was her ?
Yes , I asked her what she was doing walking around at that hour ...
And , as usual , she insulted me .
Okay , you can go . Thank you .
Are you convinced , Inspector ?
The only crime the witch has on her conscience is the one with the pins .
Yes , I know . I know as well ...
I 'm just saying , let 's investigate ...
Let 's keep her inside for a while .
I 'm sorry , Marshal , you 're like the people here , you want a culprit at any cost ?
- I just don 't want any more culprits . - Explain yourself , Marshal .
What is there to explain ?
She 's innocent . We 're all certain she 's innocent .
- Sure . - Sure , she 's innocent .
- Then let 's release her . - Yes , precisely .
Release her tomorrow morning .
Yes , sir .
What ?
An appalling crime .
That horrifies us , that makes us ashamed of ourselves .
Is this it ? We can build motorways , but we can 't overcome ignorance
and superstition .
We must find the culprits , and punish them .
Yes , sir .
Sure we will ...
We 'll arrest the entire village .
What 's going on there ?
Imbalomini ...
If you 'd kept quiet , if you hadn 't told them you 'd seen her by the fort .
- But it was the truth . - The truth ?
Look at this mess . Here 's the truth .
Who broke your doll ? What rascal did that ?
- Have you lost your tongue ? - Madam .
It 's pointless .
She doesn 't understand you .
She 's mute . She 's an abnormal child .
Dumb , you mean ?
Well that 's still no reason to play with a doll without a head .
There must be a toy shop in this village .
Yes , try that stationery store , I noticed they sell toys as well .
Good , then let 's go and buy a new one .
- Are you happy ? - Martelli .
I 'm coming .
- Madam ... - Listen , you can drop the formalities ...
My name 's Patrizia .
As you prefer , my name 's Andrea Martelli .
- A pleasure . - Martelli , are you coming ?
Wait a minute ! Goodbye .
Goodbye .
Let 's buy you a nice doll . Come on .
It 's okay . Don 't you want a doll ?
Don 't be afraid .
Come on .
Let 's go there again , they 'll come back today .
Yes , who knows when ? What if they spent all their money ?
They won 't even let you look at them without any money .
What do you think ? These cops have been sent here for nothing ?
The killer is still around here somewhere .
Let 's go back .
They just send the cops out to roast in the mountains .
Not the witch , they buried her .
You get it ? She can 't hurt us any more .
Then let 's go .
I 've got money .
They did it with Barra and he 's crazy .
And they 're young .
- What are you doing ? - I 'm not coming , I 'm scared .
You 're just scared of women .
Go back to the oratorio , you like it there .
- It 's not true . - Sure it 's true .
- It 's not true . - Go back to your mummy , I 'm going anyway .
Come back . Come back here , Mario .
Who gives a damn . Fuck you .
But ...
- Why aren 't you playing ? - I don 't feel like it .
- He 's worried about Mario . - Hold on ...
- What has he done ? - I told him to come back .
- Just tell me what he 's done ? - He went to the haunted house , alone .
Alone ?
Don . Alberto , people go there because ...
- Because women go there . - What ?
Women go there .
You 're so young .
You do these things ? Impossible .
It 's not our fault , Mario went there .
I told him it 's dangerous , that he might meet that horrible man ...
I swear on the Virgin Mary that I told him .
I said , " If he finds you in a field he 'll kill you " ...
- But he says the witch is dead . - The witch .
Could you be any more ignorant ?
And this is the result ...
Mario isn 't afraid to walk around alone because the witch is dead .
No one can be killed with black magic , no one !
- It 's nonsense . - Yes , Don . Alberto .
I told him the killer is still around .
- Yes , he is . - Yes , it 's true .
Lord , how thoughtless .
Stay here and be good . Okay ? Stay here .
Yes .
- Why did you tell Don . Alberto ? - If I didn 't say anything he 'd be dead .
Hi .
- Do you know how to change a tyre ? - If you give me the tools .
I 'll also give you 1000 lira , okay ?
What do you prefer , the money or a kiss ?
Look , More than a contusion , it 's a real wound this time .
Yes . A violent blow by a blunt weapon .
If you ask me , the autopsy will reveal that wound wasn 't fatal ...
I think he died of suffocation .
Right ...
Like the first one , like little Locascio .
The only difference being he suffocated this one .
- It was even easier . - The priest found him ...
He was walking past , he saw him ...
And he immediately realised what had happened .
He 's still here .
Well , what shall we do ?
- Shall we question him ? - It 's not the right time .
And it would nice if the journalists could leave him alone .
Marshal .
The locals can 't blame the witch this time .
I don 't think so .
It 's not a sense of guilt that you see on their faces ...
No ...
The only thing that 's certain now is that they 're scared again .
THE CLASSICS OF BLACK MAGIC
Hello .
- Hello , Montanelli . - Martelli , thank you .
Right , if you were Montanelli you wouldn 't be here .
I see you 're interested in this type of literature as well .
Yes , it interests me a great deal .
- Would you like a drink ? - No , thank you , I can 't stay .
- Then why are you here ? - I 'm returning your lighter .
There are no initials on it , how do you know it 's mine ?
You 're the only one who could have Cartier around here .
You 're right . They 're so expensive .
I 'm glad you didn 't keep it .
And you didn 't even give it any thought ?
Actually , I did give it some thought ...
About giving it to the police .
Why ?
Because I found it there , close by .
- Close to what ? - Don 't you know another boy was killed ?
Another one . I don 't know anything about it .
- But when ? - Right .
You didn 't know ?
No , I had no idea .
How could I have known ? You 're the first person I 've seen this evening .
Then where have you been ?
That 's my business .
Listen to me , you son of a bitch , I hope you don 't think I ...
That you , at an average of speed 170kmph , without ever stopping ...
In three hours , you would have driven more than five hundred kilometres .
Up and down the motorway .
Yes , up and down , like an idiot .
Why ? Is it illegal ?
Yes , in a certain sense ...
By the fuel .
At that speed , your car ...
Can go a maximum of four kilometres per litre ...
So a hundred litres wouldn 't have been enough .
My car has two fuel tanks .
Yes , I know . 40 litres each , 80 in total .
No , madam ...
I say you stopped to fill up .
Okay . I stopped .
Why did you deny it ?
Because ...
I didn 't just stop to fill up .
I also made a call , and I noticed that boy had taken my number .
And ?
And ...
I called a camp-site , in Pugnochiuso .
There were two foreigners there , two kids who had some stuff .
Drugs ?
Marijuana .
And I didn 't want to get them involved .
What is you relationship like with uncle Francesco ?
What kind of relationship are you talking about ?
I don 't have any relationship with him .
So you 've never visited him ?
No , never .
But if I told you I 'd seen you with my own eyes .
Okay , yes , I 've been to see him two or three times .
I like reading about black magic , so I ...
I 'd like to know what I 've done wrong .
I 've had enough of this village .
I know Centura like the back of my hand ...
Always going somewhere , just to do something .
I can 't talk to the people here , we don 't understand each other .
Uncle Francesco might be a scoundrel but at least he makes me laugh .
You said this camp-site is in Alberobello , right ?
Yes , it 's in Alberobello . But ...
I thought you said it was in Pugnochiuso ?
Yes , yes ... It 's in Pugnochiuso .
What do you want from me ?
Just one thing , for now ...
Don 't leave without letting us know .
You think I should have told them he changed my tyre ?
I 'd be locked up by now .
I threw the lighter away , I couldn 't care less if it 's made of gold .
You 're a bit crazy , if you ask me .
I 'm sorry , but first you throw away the lighter ...
- Then you tell me about the boy . - I have to tell someone , don 't I ?
And you 're the only normal person I know in this damned village .
Thanks , I 'm moved .
I spent a long time trying to make sense of what happened
and these people .
Look at this ...
Look at what these hypocrites are capable of .
" ANOTHER CHILD KILLED IN ACCENDURA " They make me laugh , with all their crocodile tears .
They bring flowers to the fountain where they found that poor boy ...
And the one who killed him is one of them .
And you lot encourage them .
- You know something ... - What ?
This looks like the head of the duck I gave the little girl .
Yes , macabre isn 't it ? I used that shot on purpose .
Didn 't you want to buy her a doll ?
Yes , but I didn 't like any of them , the only decent one was that duck .
- Where did you find it ? - There , on the ground .
Why was only the head there ?
- Andrea . - Yes .
- Nothing here , either . - Keep looking , keep looking .
Where did you find the duck 's head ?
Where you are now , a bit closer to me .
- It 's pointless . - Keep looking , keep looking .
Some kid might have picked it up , or a dog , perhaps .
I found it .
Well ?
Well , it 's like I said ...
That 's the priest 's house . That one there , on the corner .
Malvina went out that night , and she saw someone strangle Antonino ...
That 's why she tore off the head on the doll and the duck ...
Because she wanted to do the same thing .
Only she squeezed too hard ...
She did what she 'd seen him do .
It must have had a profound effect on her .
- A gesture of imitation . - Yes , of course , it 's possible ...
In fact it 's quite likely . Children do these things .
And Malvina ... You know about her mental condition .
Father ...
If that little girl saw the murderer ...
Do you think she 'd be able to identify him ?
If she had a good look at him , why not ?
But how do you expect her to tell you who it was ?
First of all , she 's mute , and ...
No , she 's not stupid , if that 's what you 're thinking ...
She 's retarded . She 's six years old ...
But she has the intelligence of a three year old .
But if we question her in the right way ...
We 'll be able to find out if she saw him .
Cigarette , Father ?
You 'll need a lot of patience , and a lot of kindness .
Yes , you can just imagine how nice the police will be to her .
Father , it has to be us .
My son is forgetting something important ...
Our door is always locked at night .
And it 's not because of thieves , it 's for Malvina ...
Because you never know , she might decide to go out by herself .
- You know how careful I am , Alberto . - Yes , mother , of course .
I guess this changes everything .
Madam , Some sweets for Malvina .
The door is locked at night , so Malvina didn 't see a damned thing .
And she pulled off their heads because she felt like it .
You can save all this rubbish for your newspaper .
The door was open that night .
- She left it open when she went out . - Really ?
And where did she go ? What was she doing out at that hour ?
- She killed Antonino . - How can you think such nonsense ?
Now I 'll tell you what I found out from the Marshal ...
Don . Aurelia 's husband killed himself ...
The people in the village say it was his wife 's fault .
But one thing is certain ...
That she was madly jealous of him .
She had made his life impossible .
But where the hell do the children fit in ?
You don 't think they fit in ?
All four of them went to the oratorio ...
And they stole part of her son 's affection for her ...
A bitter jealousy can even drive someone to murder .
I think that whiskey has gone to your head .
Hello ?
Tell me .
No , she 's not here .
Why ? Did she tell you ...
No , but she might have brought you a gift , to thank you ...
- For the duck and the sweets . - Silly .
Yes , of course , if she comes here .
No , don 't mention it .
- Who was it ? - Don . Alberto .
He can 't find his mother , or Malvina ...
He doesn 't know where they 've gone .
Do you know them ?
Yes , I know them , but I haven 't seen them .
Thanks . Let 's go .
We messed up , we should 've gone to the police .
Yes , smart ...
Knowing what they think of me , they probably would have arrested me .
If he kills her now , it 's our fault .
We should 've talked to her directly , we suggested it to him ...
We should have kept quiet . Poor girl .
There 's someone there .
Have you seen Don . Aurelia , the priest 's mother ?
Yes , just now , from a distance ...
With that mute girl , at the top of the mountain .
Okay , thanks .
Do you think a mother could kill her own daughter ?
If she 's crazy , yes .
Let 's get ready to assist in another nice funeral with a choir .
Cut it out . That isn 't funny .
- You don 't have children . - Do you ?
Yes , two boys .
Then you also have wife .
Pity .
Please , mother ! Give her to me .
Wait .
Alberto .
No , Alberto . Stop .
Listen to me .
- What 's going on ? - Stop him , my son is insane .
He 'll kill her .
" Malvina 's going to heaven now , mother ... "
" She 's going to heaven , with the angels . "
" I 'm not doing it for me ... "
" It 's for them . "
" I can 't let them stop me . "
" I love them like brothers ... "
" And I 'll never abandon my brothers . "
Don . Alberto .
You found her .
Great .
But you must be tired now . Very tired .
Give me the girl .
I 'll take her back to the village .
Will you ?
I 'll take her .
Come here . Come here .
Coward . Coward .
" Because women go there . They grow up ... "
" They feel the stirrings of the flesh . "
" They fall into the arms of sin . We must stop them . "
" Sin that God easily forgives , yes ... "
" But what of tomorrow ? What sordid acts will they commit ? "
" What sins will they enact when they no longer come to confession ? "
" Then they will really be dead . Dead forever . "
" I love them as though they were all my brothers . "
I absolve you in the name of the Father , the Son , and the Holy Ghost .
Amen .